{
  "id": "2b451474-9e9e-48e2-9b7f-1b957103e1bc",
  "name": "Welded Pipe and Fittings",
  "topicId": "2b451474-9e9e-48e2-9b7f-1b957103e1bc",
  "questions": [
    {
      "id": "2b451474-9e9e-48e2-9b7f-1b957103e1bc",
      "topicId": "2b451474-9e9e-48e2-9b7f-1b957103e1bc",
      "question": "What is the relationship of amount of distortion to the amount of force applied as long as a material is not stressed beyond its elastic limit?",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
          "The amount of distortion will be directly proportional to the amount of force applied.",
           "The amount of distortion will be inversely proportional to the amount of force applied.",
           "The amount of distortion will be unrelated to the amount of force applied.",
           "The amount of distortion will be exponentially related to the amount of force applied.",
           "The amount of distortion will remain constant regardless of the amount of force applied."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["The amount of distortion will be directly proportional to the amount of force applied."],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "2b451474-9e9e-48e2-9b7f-1b957103e1bc",
      "topicId": "2b451474-9e9e-48e2-9b7f-1b957103e1bc",
      "question": "What are the four (4) primary parts of a hydraulic bolt tensioner?",
      "type": "checkbox_type",
      "options": [
        "Hex socket",
        "Bridge",
        "Hydraulic load cell",
        "Puller"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Hex socket", "Bridge", "Hydraulic load cell", "Puller"],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "2b451474-9e9e-48e2-9b7f-1b957103e1bc",
      "topicId": "2b451474-9e9e-48e2-9b7f-1b957103e1bc",
      "question": "What percentage of the torque applied to a nut actually results in a pre-load tension on the stud?",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "10%",
        "15%",
        "20%",
        "11%"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["10%"],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "2b451474-9e9e-48e2-9b7f-1b957103e1bc",
      "topicId": "2b451474-9e9e-48e2-9b7f-1b957103e1bc",
      "question": "If a force of 50 lb is applied on a torque wrench at a distance of 2 feet from the centre of the stud, how much torque is being applied?",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "100 ft-lb",
        "120 ft-lb",
        "130 ft-lb",
        "200 ft-lb"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["100 ft-lb"],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "2b451474-9e9e-48e2-9b7f-1b957103e1bc",
      "topicId": "2b451474-9e9e-48e2-9b7f-1b957103e1bc",
      "question": "If a force of 75 lb is applied on a torque wrench at a distance of 36” from the centre of the stud, how much torque is being applied?",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "225 ft-lb",
        "250 ft-lb",
        "275 ft-lb",
        "200 ft-lb"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["225 ft-lb"],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "2b451474-9e9e-48e2-9b7f-1b957103e1bc",
      "topicId": "2b451474-9e9e-48e2-9b7f-1b957103e1bc",
      "question": "What is the name of the device used to get an accurate measurement of how much a fastener elongates as tension is applied?",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "Tensile tester",
        "Torque wrench",
        "Digital caliper",
        "Strain gauge",
        "Ultrasonic extensometer"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Ultrasonic extensometer"],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "2b451474-9e9e-48e2-9b7f-1b957103e1bc",
      "topicId": "2b451474-9e9e-48e2-9b7f-1b957103e1bc",
      "question": "When installing the nuts on the studs prior to torquing, how tight should the nuts be?",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
          "All nuts should thread on hand tight without requiring a wrench.",
          "All nuts should be tightened with a wrench until snug.",
          "All nuts should be tightened to half the final torque value.",
          "All nuts should be tightened to the final torque value.",
          "All nuts should be left slightly loose for final adjustment."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["All nuts should thread on hand tight without requiring a wrench."],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "2b451474-9e9e-48e2-9b7f-1b957103e1bc",
      "topicId": "2b451474-9e9e-48e2-9b7f-1b957103e1bc",
      "question": "What should be used to prevent the pressure from the nuts galling the material in the flange during torquing?",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
          "A hardened washer between the face of the nut and the flange surface.",
          "A soft washer between the face of the nut and the flange surface.",
          "A layer of lubricant on the flange surface.",
          "A rubber gasket between the nut and the flange surface.",
          "A metal shim between the nut and the flange surface."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["A hardened washer between the face of the nut and the flange surface."],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "8c3f0f14-4dc2-11ee-be56-0242ac120002",
        "topicId": "8c3f0f14-4dc2-11ee-be56-0242ac120002",
        "question": "State the formula used to calculate the centre to face measurement for a 90° long radius butt weld elbow",
        "type": "single_type",
        "options": [
          "NPS x 1 1/2.",
          "NPS x 5/8.",
          "NPS x 1."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": ["NPS x 1 1/2."],
        "explanation": ""
      },
    {
        "id": "8c3f0f14-4dc2-11ee-be56-0242ac120002",
        "topicId": "8c3f0f14-4dc2-11ee-be56-0242ac120002",
        "question": "State the formula used to calculate the centre to face measurement for a 45° long radius butt weld elbow",
        "type": "single_type",
        "options": [
          "NPS x 1 1/2.",
          "NPS x 5/8.",
          "NPS x 1."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": ["NPS x 5/8."],
        "explanation": ""
      },
    {
        "id": "8c3f0f14-4dc2-11ee-be56-0242ac120002",
        "topicId": "8c3f0f14-4dc2-11ee-be56-0242ac120002",
        "question": "State the formula used to calculate the centre to face measurement for a 90° short radius butt weld elbow.",
        "type": "single_type",
        "options": [
          "NPS x 1 1/2.",
          "NPS x 5/8.",
          "NPS x 1."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": ["NPS x 1."],
        "explanation": ""
      },
    {
        "id": "8c3f0f14-4dc2-11ee-be56-0242ac120002",
        "topicId": "8c3f0f14-4dc2-11ee-be56-0242ac120002",
        "question": "Using either the previous method or an alternative method, calculate the centre to face measurement for an 8'' (200 mm) long radius butt weld 45° elbow. Show your work.",
        "type": "text_type",
        "options": [],
        "correctAnswer": ["5"],
        "explanation": "Method 1) = NPS x 5/8 = 8'' x 5/8 = 5''. Method 2) NPS x 1/2 x 1/2 = 4''. Add the 1st and 3rd answers. 8'' x 1/2 = 4'' x 1/2 = 2'' x 1/2 = 1when power or energy cannot flow due to the position of a disconnecting switch. Add 1st and 3rd, 4'' + 1'' = 5''."
    },
      {
        "id": "8c3f0f14-4dc2-11ee-be56-0242ac120002",
        "topicId": "8c3f0f14-4dc2-11ee-be56-0242ac120002",
        "question": "Calculate the centre to face measurement for a 10'' (250 mm) long radius butt weld 90° elbow. Show your work.",
        "type": "text_type",
        "options": [],
        "correctAnswer": ["15"],
        "explanation": "NPS x 1 1/2 = 10'' x 1 1/2 = 15''."
      },
      {
        "id": "8c3f0f14-4dc2-11ee-be56-0242ac120002",
        "topicId": "8c3f0f14-4dc2-11ee-be56-0242ac120002",
        "question": "Do all unions require a gasket to ensure a proper seal?",
        "type": "single_type",
        "options": [
          "Yes",
          "No"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": ["No"],
        "explanation": ""
      },
      {
        "id": "8c3f0f14-4dc2-11ee-be56-0242ac120002",
        "topicId": "8c3f0f14-4dc2-11ee-be56-0242ac120002",
        "question": "For a 6'' x 6'' x 3'' std. butt weld tee, what does the 3'' tell you?",
        "type": "single_type",
        "options": [
            "The branch outlet is 3'' NPS.",
            "The main run size is 3''.",
            "The fitting length is 3''.",
            "The wall thickness is 3''.",
            "The pressure rating is 3''."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": ["The branch outlet is 3'' NPS."],
        "explanation": ""
      },
      {
        "id": "8c3f0f14-4dc2-11ee-be56-0242ac120002",
        "topicId": "8c3f0f14-4dc2-11ee-be56-0242ac120002",
        "question": "For the previous question, what is the fitting allowance for the branch opening?",
        "type": "text_type",
        "options": [],
        "correctAnswer": ["4 7/8", "5", "4.875", "4,875"],
        "explanation": "Refer to your IPT Pipe Trades Handbook. The fitting allowance is 4 7/8''."
      },
      {
        "id": "8c3f0f14-4dc2-11ee-be56-0242ac120002",
        "topicId": "8c3f0f14-4dc2-11ee-be56-0242ac120002",
        "question": "What would the fitting allowance be for a 2'' 3000# SW tee?",
        "type": "text_type",
        "options": [],
        "correctAnswer": ["1 1/2", "1,5", "1.5"],
        "explanation": "Refer to your IPT Pipe Trades Handbook. The fitting allowance is 1 1/2''."
      },
      {
        "id": "8c3f0f14-4dc2-11ee-be56-0242ac120002",
        "topicId": "8c3f0f14-4dc2-11ee-be56-0242ac120002",
        "question": "A class 6000# forged steel threaded coupling is taken to be equivalent to a steel pipe classification of ____________ and a class 6000# forged steel socket weld coupling to be equivalent to a steel pipe classification of ____________.",
        "type": "single_type",
        "options": [
            "XXS; Sch. 160",
            "XXS; Sch. 120",
            "XXS; Sch. 80",
            "XXS; Sch. 40"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": ["XXS; Sch. 160"],
        "explanation": ""
      },
      {
        "id": "8c3f0f14-4dc2-11ee-be56-0242ac120002",
        "topicId": "8c3f0f14-4dc2-11ee-be56-0242ac120002",
        "question": "List the accepted procedure for making a butt weld joint.",
        "type": "checkbox_type",
        "options": [
          "Measure",
          "Mark",
          "Cut",
          "Bevel",
          "Fit-up",
          "Tack",
          "Ream"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": ["Measure", "Mark", "Cut", "Bevel", "Fit-up", "Tack", "Ream"],
        "explanation": ""
      },
      {
        "id": "8c3f0f14-4dc2-11ee-be56-0242ac120002",
        "topicId": "8c3f0f14-4dc2-11ee-be56-0242ac120002",
        "question": "What would you use a wraparound for?",
        "type": "single_type",
        "options": [
            "A wraparound is used to mark the cut path to be followed around a pipe.",
            "A wraparound is used to insulate pipes.",
            "A wraparound is used to secure pipes together.",
            "A wraparound is used to measure the diameter of a pipe.",
            "A wraparound is used to protect pipes from corrosion."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": ["A wraparound is used to mark the cut path to be followed around a pipe."],
        "explanation": ""
      },
      {
        "id": "8c3f0f14-4dc2-11ee-be56-0242ac120002",
        "topicId": "8c3f0f14-4dc2-11ee-be56-0242ac120002",
        "question": "The land width for a butt weld is typically _____ and _____ (may/may not) vary in accordance with a QCM or weld procedure.",
        "type": "single_type",
        "options": [
          "1/8''; 1/16''",
          "1/7''; 1/16''",
          "1/8''; 1/10''",
          "1/5''; 1/16''"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": ["1/8''; 1/16''"],
        "explanation": ""
      },
      {
        "id": "8c3f0f14-4dc2-11ee-be56-0242ac120002",
        "topicId": "8c3f0f14-4dc2-11ee-be56-0242ac120002",
        "question": "When should a gap rod be removed from a butt weld?",
        "type": "single_type",
        "options": [
            "After the second tack.",
            "Before the first tack.",
            "After the first tack.",
            "Before the second tack.",
            "After the final weld is complete."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": ["After the second tack."],
        "explanation": ""
      },
      {
        "id": "8c3f0f14-4dc2-11ee-be56-0242ac120002",
        "topicId": "8c3f0f14-4dc2-11ee-be56-0242ac120002",
        "question": "What recommended bevel angle should be ground onto the flat end of a pipe?",
        "type": "single_type",
        "options": [
          "37 degrees.",
          "37 1/2 degrees.",
          "90 degrees.",
          "45 degrees."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": ["37 1/2 degrees."],
        "explanation": ""
      },
      {
        "id": "8c3f0f14-4dc2-11ee-be56-0242ac120002",
        "topicId": "8c3f0f14-4dc2-11ee-be56-0242ac120002",
        "question": "A socket-weld fitting has two weld locations: one inside and one outside.",
        "type": "single_type",
        "options": [
          "True",
          "False"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": ["False"],
        "explanation": ""
      },
      {
        "id": "8c3f0f14-4dc2-11ee-be56-0242ac120002",
        "topicId": "8c3f0f14-4dc2-11ee-be56-0242ac120002",
        "question": "What is another name for a Van Stone flange?",
        "type": "single_type",
        "options": [
            "A lap joint flange.",
            "A slip-on flange.",
            "A weld neck flange.",
            "A blind flange.",
            "A socket weld flange."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": ["A lap joint flange."],
        "explanation": ""
      },
      {
        "id": "8c3f0f14-4dc2-11ee-be56-0242ac120002",
        "topicId": "8c3f0f14-4dc2-11ee-be56-0242ac120002",
        "question": "You would find a screwed companion flange on an 8'' (200 mm), 900 psi flanged joint.",
        "type": "single_type",
        "options": [
          "True",
          "False"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": ["False"],
        "explanation": ""
      },
      {
        "id": "8c3f0f14-4dc2-11ee-be56-0242ac120002",
        "topicId": "8c3f0f14-4dc2-11ee-be56-0242ac120002",
        "question": "A 600# RFWNF has a face that is raised: a) 1/16'' (1.6 mm). b) 1/4'' (6.35 mm). c) 1/2'' (13 mm).",
        "type": "single_type",
        "options": [
          "1/16'' (1.6 mm).",
          "1/4'' (6.35 mm).",
          "1/2'' (13 mm)."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": ["1/4'' (6.35 mm)."],
        "explanation": ""
      },
      {
        "id": "8c3f0f14-4dc2-11ee-be56-0242ac120002",
        "topicId": "8c3f0f14-4dc2-11ee-be56-0242ac120002",
        "question": "What is the best sealing surface for corrosive and high temperature/pressure flanged joints?",
        "type": "single_type",
        "options": [
            "A ring joint flange.",
            "A lap joint flange.",
            "A flat face flange.",
            "A raised face flange.",
            "A tongue and groove flange."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": ["A ring joint flange."],
        "explanation": ""
      },
      {
        "id": "8c3f0f14-4dc2-11ee-be56-0242ac120002",
        "topicId": "8c3f0f14-4dc2-11ee-be56-0242ac120002",
        "question": "Cast iron flanges are commonly available in pressure ratings of ___________ and ___________.",
        "type": "single_type",
        "options": [
          "125#, 250#",
          "150#, 250#",
          "125#, 200#",
          "150#, 200#"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": ["125#, 250#"],
        "explanation": ""
      },
      {
        "id": "8c3f0f14-4dc2-11ee-be56-0242ac120002",
        "topicId": "8c3f0f14-4dc2-11ee-be56-0242ac120002",
        "question": "What size and number of studs are required for bolting up a 12'' 600# flanged joint?",
        "type": "single_type",
        "options": [
            "1 1/4'' x 8'' bolts and 20 bolts are required.",
            "1 1/2'' x 9'' bolts and 24 bolts are required.",
            "1'' x 7'' bolts and 18 bolts are required.",
            "1 1/4'' x 6'' bolts and 20 bolts are required.",
            "1'' x 8'' bolts and 16 bolts are required."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": ["1 1/4'' x 8'' bolts and 20 bolts are required."],
        "explanation": ""
      },
      {
        "id": "8c3f0f14-4dc2-11ee-be56-0242ac120002",
        "topicId": "8c3f0f14-4dc2-11ee-be56-0242ac120002",
        "question": "What size of open end/box end wrench is required for the previous question? (Clues: 2H nuts; show formula.)",
        "type": "text_type",
        "options": [],
        "correctAnswer": ["16/8", "2"],
        "explanation": "Wrench size = bolt size x 1 1/2 + 1/8'', (1 1/4 x 1 1/2) + 1/8 = (5/4 x 3/2) + 1/8 = 15/8 + 1/8 = 16/8 or 2''."
      },
      {
        "id": "8c3f0f14-4dc2-11ee-be56-0242ac120002",
        "topicId": "8c3f0f14-4dc2-11ee-be56-0242ac120002",
        "question": "What size and number of studs are required for bolting up a 4'' 150# RF flanged joint?",
        "type": "single_type",
        "options": [
            "5/8'' x 3 1/2'' bolts and 8 bolts are required.",
            "3/4'' x 4'' bolts and 8 bolts are required.",
            "1/2'' x 3'' bolts and 10 bolts are required.",
            "5/8'' x 4'' bolts and 8 bolts are required.",
            "3/4'' x 3 1/2'' bolts and 10 bolts are required."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": ["5/8'' x 3 1/2'' bolts and 8 bolts are required."],
        "explanation": ""
      },
      {
        "id": "8c3f0f14-4dc2-11ee-be56-0242ac120002",
        "topicId": "8c3f0f14-4dc2-11ee-be56-0242ac120002",
        "question": "What size of open end/box end wrench is required for the previous question? (Clues: 2H nuts; show formula.)",
        "type": "text_type",
        "options": [],
        "correctAnswer": ["17/16", "1 1/16", "1.0625", "1,0625"],
        "explanation": "Wrench size = bolt size x 1 1/2 + 1/8'', (5/8 x 1 1/2) + 1/8 = (5/8 x 3/2) + 1/8 = 15/16 or 1 1/16''."
      },
      {
        "id": "8c3f0f14-4dc2-11ee-be56-0242ac120002",
        "topicId": "8c3f0f14-4dc2-11ee-be56-0242ac120002",
        "question": "What are the three (3) categories of gaskets?",
        "type": "checkbox_type",
        "options": [
          "Soft",
          "Spiral wound",
          "Metallic"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": ["Soft", "Spiral wound", "Metallic"],
        "explanation": ""
      },
      {
        "id": "8c3f0f14-4dc2-11ee-be56-0242ac120002",
        "topicId": "8c3f0f14-4dc2-11ee-be56-0242ac120002",
        "question": "A metallic ring gasket is usually made of a product that is a) Equal in hardness to the flange material. b) Harder than the flange material. c) Softer than the flange material.",
        "type": "single_type",
        "options": [
          "Equal in hardness to the flange material.",
          "Harder than the flange material.",
          "Softer than the flange material."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": ["Harder than the flange material."],
        "explanation": ""
      },
      {
        "id": "8c3f0f14-4dc2-11ee-be56-0242ac120002",
        "topicId": "8c3f0f14-4dc2-11ee-be56-0242ac120002",
        "question": "Which two (2) tools are required to make a gasket using the trace and tap method?",
        "type": "checkbox_type",
        "options": [
          "Hammer",
          "Ball peen",
          "Scissors",
          "Knife",
          "Punch"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": ["Hammer", "Ball peen"],
        "explanation": ""
      }
    ]
  }
